Trevor P. Stewart

Contact Information

Department of Physics University of Toronto 60 St. George St. M5S1A7Toronto, Ontario Canada

Office Phone +1 (416) 978-8478 $Home\ Phone\ +1\ (647)\ 273-8702$ E-mail stewartt@physics.utoronto.ca

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research has chiefly focused on high- Q^2 neutral and charged current deep inelastic scattering and charm production. However, I am interested in a wide range of topics in high energy experimental particle physics, especially those that can be studied at the LHC: Higgs and new physics beyond the standard model (BSM) searches and precision QCD and electroweak measurements.

At ZEUS, my main experience with detector hardware has been the calorimeter and the trigger. While both of these are of great interest to me, I would also like to gain experience with the operation of other detector components such as muon or tracking detectors.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada

PhD. Physics

July 2012

- Thesis topic: Measurement of High-Q² Neutral Current cross-sections with longitudinally polarised positrons with the ZEUS Detector
- Supervisor: Prof. John Martin
- Area of Study: Experimental Particle Physics

MSc, Physics August 2007

- Thesis topic: Charm production in High-Q² Charged Current Deep Inelastic Scat-
- Supervisor: Prof. John Martin
- Area of Study: Experimental Particle Physics

University of New Brunswick (UNB), Fredericton, New Brunswick, Canada I was enrolled in a joint program for science and computer science and received two separate undergraduate degrees.

BSc, Physics December 2005

• Graduated with Honours

• Graduated with First Division

BCS, Computer Science

December 2005

AND

PROCEEDINGS

CONFERENCES Trevor Stewart, speaker at The Europhysics Conference of High-Energy Physics, Grenoble, France, July 21-27, 2011. Measurement of High-Q² Charged and Neutral Current Deep Inelastic e⁺p Scattering Cross Sections with a Longitudinally Polarised Positron Beam at HERA. Proceedings in PoS EPS-HEP2011:367.

> Trevor Stewart, speaker at The XIX International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects, Newport News, VA, USA, April 11-15, 2011. Measurement of High-Q² Neutral and Charged Current Deep Inelastic e⁺p Scattering Cross Sections with a Longitudinally Polarised Positron Beam at HERA. Proceedings to appear in

Proceedings of 19th International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects.

RECENT ZEUS PLENARY TALKS

Trevor Stewart, speaker at the ZEUS Collaboration Meeting, Hamburg, Germany, September 21-23 2011. High- Q^2 e^+p Neutral Current Analysis - Update.

Trevor Stewart, speaker at the ZEUS Collaboration Meeting, Hamburg, Germany, October 11-13 2010. NC DIS in 06- $07 e^+p$ data.

Trevor Stewart, speaker at the ZEUS Collaboration Meeting, Kiev, Ukraine, October 5-9 2009. Charm Production in CC.

AWARDS

Major Awards

- Ontario Graduate Scholarship (OGS), 2007-2008
- Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC) Undergraduate Student Research Award, Summer 2004

University of New Brunswick (UNB)

- Dr. A. Wilmer Duff Memorial Prize, 2005-2006
- Frank and Isa Pridham Memorial Scholarship, 2001-2002
- UNB Fredericton Scholarship Guarantee, 2000-2001

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Student

March 2006 to present

- Developed an analysis for charm production in charged current deep inelastic scattering analysis using reconstructed secondary verticies and impact parameter techniques. This analysis was the first observation of charm production in charged current deep inelastic scattering at ZEUS by this technique.
- Developed an analysis for high- Q^2 neutral current e^+p deep inelastic scattering using the HERA polarised positron beam. This analysis measured the single differential cross-sections, the reduced cross-sections, observed parity violation at high- Q^2 and in combination with the previously published HERA-II e^-p analysis, made the most precise determination of $xF_3^{\gamma Z}$.
- Measured the shape of the Z_{vtx} distribution for the 2006-2007 positron running period at ZEUS. Showed the need for multiple Z_{vtx} measurements within the running period. Implemented a correction based on this measurement.
- Worked on validating the common ntuple (CN) project at ZEUS using both the charm production in charged current analysis and the neutral current analysis.
 The goal of the CN project is to provide ntuples suitable for a wide range of analysis and long term storage of ZEUS data.
- Contributed to the running, maintenance and calibration of the ZEUS calorimeter.

Summer Research Assistant

May 2005 to August 2005

• Continuation of work on the ZEUS Third Level Trigger.

Studied the effects of backsplash from the ZEUS calorimeter on the measurement
of the kinematic variables using jets. Implemented this correction for use in
high-Q² neutral current deep inelastic scattering.

Summer Research Assistant

May 2004 to August 2004

• Assisted with the maintenance, operation, debugging and updating of the ZEUS Third Level Trigger (TLT).

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

University of Toronto

Teaching Assistant

September 2008 to April 2010

- Instructor for PHY 224 Practical Physics I (Laboratory)
 - 4 semesters
 - Responsible for the supervision of a 3 hour lab where first year physics and engineering science students are introduced to basic laboratory and data analysis skills through the study of historical experiments from a variety of fields in physics. Special attention was paid to error analysis, data collection techniques and experimental design.
 - Responsible for evaluation of weekly laboratory reports, formal experiment write-ups and oral presentations.

Teaching Assistant

September 2007 to April 2008

- Instructor for PHY 151/152 Foundations of Physics (Laboratory)
 - 2 semesters
 - Responsible for the supervision of a 3 hour lab where first year physics students are introduced to the fundamentals of mechanics using micro-computer based data collection and analysis.
 - Responsible for evaluation of weekly laboratory reports and formal experiment write-ups.

University of New Brunswick

Teaching Assistant

September 2005 to December 2005

- Instructor for PHYS 1081 Foundations of Physics for Engineers (Laboratory)
 - 1 semester
 - Responsible for the supervision of a 3 hour lab where first year engineering students are introduced to the fundamentals of mechanics through hands-on laboratory work.
 - Responsible for evaluation of weekly laboratory reports and formal experiment write-ups.

PUBLICATIONS 48 ZEUS publications, see

http://inspirehep.net/search?ln=en&p=

 $FIND+A+STEWART\%2C+TREVOR+P\&of=hb\&action_search=Search for reference.$

Participlated in the analysis of the following papers:

• S. Chekanov et al. [ZEUS Collaboration], Measurement of high-Q² neutral current deep inelastic e⁻p scattering cross sections with a longitudinally polarised electron beam at HERA Eur. Phys. J. C **62**, 625 (2009)

Two papers are being readied for publication submission:

- Measurement of positron-proton neutral current cross sections at high Bjorken-x with the ZEUS detector at HERA.
- Measurement of high- Q^2 neutral current deep inelastic e^+p scattering cross sections with a longitudinally polarised electron beam at HERA

COMPUTER SKILLS

Operating systems: Linux, Unix, Mac OS X and Windows.

Programming languages: Good knowledge of C, C++, FORTRAN, perl and UNIX shell scripting. Some knowledge of 8086 and 68HC11 assembler and JAVA.

High energy physics programs: Batch computing, PAW/HBOOK, ROOT. Some familiarity with event generators and simulations (GEANT).

LANGUAGES

Fluent in English and basic knowledge of French and Japanese.

REFERENCES

- Prof. John Martin (martin@physics.utoronto.ca), University of Toronto, Supervisor.
- Prof. Sampa Bhadra (bhadra@yorku.ca), York University.
- Prof. Aharon Levy (levy@alzt.tau.ac.il), Tel Aviv University and ZEUS Spokesperson.